Guide to the Zeitgeist Gallery Records MSS.400
Fales Library and Special Collections
Zeitgeist Gallery Records
2000-2009
Fales Library and Special Collections
Hernandez, Katt
Zeitgeist Gallery (Cambridge, Mass.)
MSS.400
0.75 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes
The Zeitgeist Gallery was an art space in Cambridge, Massachusetts, founded in 1994 by Alan Nidle and Karen Boutet. It hosted art exhibits, concerts, film screenings, and spoken word performances. The Zeitgeist Gallery Records document events held at the gallery between 2000 and 2005, as well as the summer of 2009, and consist of digitized materia. Included are fliers, the gallery's monthly calendar magazine, incorporating documents, correspondence, meeting minutes, and photographs.
Scope and Contents
The Zeitgeist Gallery Records documents events held at the Zeitgeist Gallery in Cambridge, Massachusetts between 2000 and 2005, as well as the summer of 2009. The collection consists of digitized material created and collected by the staff of the Zeitgeist Gallery. The material consists mainly of fliers for art exhibits, concerts, spoken word performances, and film screenings, and issues of The Zeitgeist Improbable, the gallery's monthly calendar magazine. Also included are photocopies of incorporating documents; correspondence and legal documents regarding a legal suit the gallery owner brought against a neighbor in Cambridge; meeting minutes for gallery staff meetings; photographs of staff and events; and policies for performers and gallery staff.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged by format or topic of material.
Historical Note
The Zeitgeist Gallery was an art space in Cambridge, Massachusetts, founded in 1994 by Alan Nidle and Karen Boutet. It hosted art exhibits, concerts, film screenings, and spoken word performances.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was loaned to New York University for digitization in January 2014 by Katt Hernandez.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Custodial History
In 2014 the original documents were loaned to New York University by Katt Hernandez. Following physical processing of the collection by a student assistant in the Fales Library & Special Collection, the material was digitized by two student assistants from the Avery Fisher Center for Music & Media under the guidance of a staff member from Digital Library Technical Services. After digitization was completed in the summer of 2015, the material was held by the Head of the Avery Fisher Center for Music & Media. The original documents are to be returned to the donor in the summer of 2019.
Existence and Location of Originals
The originals are held by Katt Hernandez.
Art galleries (institutions); Fliers (printed matter); Hernandez, Katt
- Administrative Papers, 2000-2003; cuid36156 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Unidentified [Folder 1 of 3], Undated; cuid36157 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Unidentified [Folder 2 of 3], Undated; cuid36158 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Unidentified [Folder 3 of 3], Undated; cuid36159 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Events, 2000, cuid36160 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Events, 2001 [Folder 1 of 2], cuid36161 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Events, 2001 [Folder 2 of 2], cuid36162 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Events, 2002 [Folder 1 of 5], cuid36163 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Events, 2002 [Folder 2 of 5], cuid36164 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Events, 2002 [Folder 3 of 5], cuid36165 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Events, 2002 [Folder 4 of 5], cuid36166 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Events, 2002 [Folder 5 of 5], cuid36167 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Events, 2003 [Folder 1 of 6], cuid36168 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Events, 2003 [Folder 2 of 6], cuid36169 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Events, 2003 [folder 3 of 6], cuid36170 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Events, 2003 [Folder 4 of 6], cuid36171 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Events, 2003 [Folder 5 of 6], cuid36172 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Events, 2003 [Folder 6 of 6], cuid36173 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Events, 2004 [Folder 1 of 2], cuid36174 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Events, 2004 [Folder 2 of 2], cuid36175 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Events, 2005, cuid36176 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Events, 2008, cuid36177 (Box 2, Folder 7)